

WALID ZIOUCHE

• DETAILS •

Annaba Algeria +213 550 04 10 30 hi@walid.dev

LINKS

Personal Website

Github

Twitter

SKILLS

Golang / TS / Python / Rust

Infrastructure As Code

CI/CD

Generalist

Tooling & Developer Experience

AWS

GCP

HOBBIES

Soccer football, gaming

LANGUAGES

English

Arabic

French

PROFILE

A software engineer from the <u>beautiful</u> city of <u>Annaba</u>, <u>Algeria</u> with more than a decade experience in software engineering.

I had the opportunity to work on some challenging problems, these include scaling Elasticsearch, creating software & infrastructures that process millions of records a day, deploying serverless apps on AWS/GCP, tinkering with Unicode and ligatures with Golang, chasing memory leaks within Python programs, or even playing with Rust and its compile time strictness.

I had especially an extensive Python experience back in 2013 using Flask, SQLAlchemy, Celery, Redis. I helped to build one of Algeria's first SAAS-based Learning Management System (LMS): coursella.com, I love making CLIs, I'm a Linux fan and I mostly live in the terminal, I get obsessed with making systems and programs run safer and faster,

On the social side, I like to advocate for opensource, I helped to organize a Linux install party, a <u>local Hackathon</u>, a <u>TEDx</u>, local <u>dev workshops</u>, or a jury in the <u>Algeria Web Awards</u> national competition, I used to <u>blog and write tech news in Arabic</u>.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer at On Deck, Remote

November 2021 — August 2022

I was a devops engineer responsible for the CI/CD, infrastructure (using <u>IaC</u>), database and the overall stability/performance of <u>On Deck</u>'s platforms.

I have also worked on improving the overall developer experience and the quality of the monorepo.

Tech Lead at SeriesCode, Remote

July 2016 — November 2021

AuxTeams (now Series Code) is a U.S. company that builds custom software for Fortune 500 companies and start-ups alike.

I was a Senior lead developer (team captain) at Series Code, managing teams, and taking care of the clients projects.

I have dealt with different kinds of projects, stacks and missions. These include building infrastructure on AWS that processes hundred millions records a day with terabytes of data storage, build serverless and event-driven projects and in many cases play the role of a site reliability engineer.

"Top Rated Plus" Freelancer at Upwork, Remote

July 2016 — May 2020

I had active contracts on Upwork on the side before going full-time. Being a Top Rated for years, the "Plus" is an extra recognition by Upwork for high-achieving professionals.

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~015817df645cb6c9b7

Co-Founder at Pinnovate, Annaba, Algeria

December 2013 — April 2018

The company behind <u>coursella.com</u>, Algeria's first Learning Management System. We won a national startup competition by Ooredoo back in 2013. I was one of the core developers of the plaform and a co-founder.

Tech Content Creator - Part time - at Hsoub, Remote

April 2015 — July 2016

https://www.hsoub.com/en/

Software Developer at Legend Algerie, Annaba, Algeria

December 2013 — December 2015

Legend Algerie was a manufacturer of custom low-cost Android-based tablets and phones targeting the Algerian market, mainly geared towards kids and e-learning. I was a founding engineer taking care of the backend and some Arabic translation work.

EDUCATION

Master In Computer Science, Badji Mokhtar University, Annaba, Algeria

September 2009 — July 2014

REFERENCES

Past co-workers from On Deck

https://www.kudoboard.com/boards/hBhEOc5G?rid=0e521eda#view



VOLUNTEERING

Mentor, Organizer at Annaba TechDays

September 2018 — September 2021

https://annaba.tech/

Jury at Algeria Web Awards (AWA)

https://www.awa.dz/

Organizer at Hackathon Annaba, Annaba, Algeria

http://hackathonannaba.com/en/

Organizer at TEDx, Annaba

https://www.ted.com/tedx/events/3533

Microsoft Student Partner at Microsoft Algeria

September 2011 — July 2012